<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Shortlog</title><link>http://www.sudhanshumishra.in/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://www.sudhanshumishra.in/feeds/lenovo.tag.rss.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2013 23:10:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><item><title>Linux and Lenovo Essential G580</title><link>http://www.sudhanshumishra.in/linux-and-lenovo-essential-g580</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Lenovo Essential G580 is the laptop which has highest number of conflicts with
aLinux &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt;. The biggest problem is when you install a Linux &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt; you will
&lt;strong&gt;lose access to your &lt;span class="caps"&gt;BIOS&lt;/span&gt; setup&lt;/strong&gt; and that&amp;#8217;s permanent. I faced this
problem and I sent my laptop to service center to repair and they had to
change its motherboard to fix this problem. When my laptop returned
after repairing I installed Ubuntu 12.10 and lost my &lt;span class="caps"&gt;BIOS&lt;/span&gt; once again!&amp;nbsp;:(&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I am using only Ubuntu 12.10 and not windows and that too without
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;BIOS&lt;/span&gt; even if it&amp;#8217;s under&amp;nbsp;warranty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now when the Ubuntu is installed, be prepared to face challenges! Ubuntu
is supposed to carry each and every driver with it but unfortunately it
doesn&amp;#8217;t have the wired network driver for this laptop. After searching
over the internet for hours I finally installed my network driver and
uploaded the installer to Google drive for future.
I solved one more issue of uncontrollable brightness of the screen by
editing grub. Bluetooth automatically gets activated sometimes.
There are uncountable number of problems. The only thing which you can
do is to prevent yourself from buying this&amp;nbsp;laptop.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sudhanshu Mishra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2013 23:10:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>tag:www.sudhanshumishra.in,2013-08-10:linux-and-lenovo-essential-g580</guid><category>BIOS</category><category>Lenovo</category><category>Lenovo G580</category><category>Linux</category><category>Ubuntu</category></item></channel></rss>